In the last lecture, we implemented or we started implementing the burger builder
Ve biz uyguladmz Son Konuma ya da Burgert kurucusunu uygulamaya baladk.
but a lot is missing.
Ama ok eksik.
It's now time to continue our work there and make sure that we do add the burger related components and
imdi almalarmza devam etme ve bumerere ait bileenleri ve zellikle burger bileenlerini eklediimizden emin
especially the burger ingredients. For that, I'll go to the components folder and I'll create a new subfolder
olmamzn zaman geldi; bu nedenle, bileen klasrne gidip adlandracamz yeni bir alt klasr
which I'll name
deitireceim.
burger,
Burger.
everything burger related shall go in there.
Ilgili burger her ey oraya gidecek.
And again this is a good way of structuring your project because as you might imagine, in bigger projects,
nk iyi bir uygulamadr ve ayrntl paralar deil byk paralar oluturmak iin tepki verin.
in very big projects, it can get hard to manage all these components since it is a good practice in
Ve yine bu, projenizi yaplandrmann iyi bir yoludur nk daha byk projelerde ve ok
react to create granular components and not big chunks.
byk projelerde hayal edebileceiniz gibi tm bu bileenleri ynetmek zor olabilir,
Now if you have a lot of components, you have a lot of files and to keep these files manageable, you want
Bir sr dosyanz varsa ve bir sr dosyanz varsa ve bu dosyalar ynetilebilir
to create a folder structure which is not only divided in components and containers but where inside
tutmak iin yalnzca bileen ve kaplara blnm olmann yan sra, bileenlerin ierdii kaplar olan bir klasr
the components and containers,
yaps oluturmak istiyorsanz.
you also divide it up by feature area so that you quickly know okay if I need to work on the burger side,
Ayrca, zellik alanna gre bldnzden burger zerinde almam gerekiyorsa hzl bir ekilde bildiinizden
I have to go into the burger folder. Now in there,
ve orada Bergere klasrne girmek zorunda kalacam.
we will add a couple of subcomponents,
Birka Suppe bileeni ekleyeceiz.
for example there, I will add the burger.js file which should be the burger we really are rendering to
rnein orada gerekten burger olmal burger js dosyasn
the screen.
ekleyeceiz.
Now I can already say that the burger alone won't do the trick though,
imdi her zaman sadece burgerin hile yapmayacan syleyebilirim.
we need ingredients in that burger like bread, the salad, the meat, the cheese, the bacon,
Ekmek gibi o burgerde peynirin etine pastrma satmak iin malzemelere ihtiyacmz var.
so for that, I'll create another subfolder here,
Bunun iin hepsi burada bir alt klasr oluturuyor.
the burger ingredient.
Hamburger malzemesi.
And in there, I'll add a BurgerIngredient.js
Ve sonra hepsi bir burger maddesi ekler.
file and actually I want to start with that ingredient because well that is actually what we need
bileenle balamak istiyorum nk aslnda ekrana bir ey gstermek iin ihtiya duyduum ey bu.
to render something to the screen.
JS dosyas ve aslnda bu
Now for the burger ingredients, I prepared a css file
imdi burger maddeleri iin bir C SS d hazrladm.
you can find attach to this video which contains a lot of css code to render burger ingredients with
Hamburger malzemelerini CSSA ile ilemek iin bir sr C S S kodunu ieren bu videoyu,
css only without importing any image which of course is great
yalnzca elbette harika bir resim almadan eklemek mmkndr.
from a file size perspective, it means not that much code or content has to be downloaded by the end user.
Fafa'nn perspektifinden bakldnda, son kullanc tarafndan bu kadar ok kod veya ieriin indirilmesi gerekmez.
Now feel free to download that css code and paste it into a newly created file,
Artk l CSSA kodunu indirmekten ve yeni oluturulan bir dosyaya yaptrmaktan ekinmeyin.
the burger ingredient css file.
Bergere maddesinin C S S dosyas.
Once you've copied in what I just shared, you have all the css fies you need to render burger
yapmsnzdr: Bergere malzemelerini vermeniz gerekir, ancak elbette ki tek bana bir ey yapmazsnz.
ingredients but that alone of course won't do anything,
Birlikte paylatm eyleri kopyaladktan sonra, tm C-lerini u ekilde
we also need to fill the burger ingredient component with life.
Hayatta bir burger bileeni bileeninin tamamna ihtiyacmz var.
That as always shall be a function
Her zaman olduu gibi bu bir ilev olacaktr.
so a stateless component and I'll name it BurgerIngredient and I expect to get some props and I want
Bu yzden bir devlet daha az bileen ve Burger madde adn ve baz sahne almak iin beklemek ve bir ey
to return something and I will use the curly braces because I actually want to run some logic before
iade etmek istiyorum ve ben aslnda dnmeden nce baz mantk altrmak istiyorum nk kvrck parantez
I return
kullanacaz.
jsx. I will also import react here because I will write some jsx in the end
Sonunda baz GSX yazacamdan GSX deitireceim veya tepki vereceim.
and of course, I will export this as the default,
Ve elbette bunu varsaylan olarak verecektir.
this function and you may very well write a snippet for your editor for creating a stateless component
Bu ilev ve eyaletten daha az bir bileen oluturmak iin editrnz iin ok iyi bir snippet yazabilirsiniz, nk
because it always looks like this
her zaman byle grnr.
react import, a function and the export,
Bir fonksiyonu ve da aktarma ilemini yeniden balatn.
feel free to write a snippet for your editor.
Editrnz iin bir snippet yazmakta ekinmeyin.
Now back to our component though, we got our burger ingredient and I said that I would need some logic
Geri bileene geri dndk, Bergere bileenimiz var ve GSX kodunu oluturmak iin baz
to render the jsx code.
mantklara ihtiyacmz olduunu syledim.
This logic is required because there are different types of ingredients and I expect to get the information
Bu mantk farkl tipteki maddeler olduundan ve hangi bileenin ilenecei hakknda bilgi
about which ingredient to render
almak istedii iin gereklidir.
via props. Now here, I will create an ingredient variable and set it to null initially,
Neden buraya gelin imdi bir madde deikeni oluturacam ve balangta null deerine ayarlayacam.
so initially we won't render anything,
Bu yzden balangta bir ey yaratmayacaz.
for example if something invalid is passed in. Now I will switch, normal javascript switch statement and
rnein, geersiz bir ey geerse, normal javascript switch ifadesini deitireceim ve ieriimin
analyze the type of my ingredient so type is a property I expect to receive
trn analiz ederek almam beklediim bir zellik olarak yazacam.
and now, we have a couple of different cases,
Ve imdi birka farkl durumumuz var.
for example, bread-bottom.
rnein Brad alt.
You are free to define this case as you want,
Bu davay istediiniz gibi tanmlamakta zgrsnz.
just make sure to then use it throughout
Sadece dolandrclk kullandnzdan emin olun.
the application if you plan on passing.
Gei yapmay planlyorsanz bavuru.
well the bottom bread of your burger. CSS classes for all these things were defined here
Bunlarn hepsi iin burger CSSA snflarnzn alttaki Brad'leri burada bulunacakt.
we will apply them soon and these will apply the correct stylings.
Onlar yaknda uygulayacaz ve DS, Starling'in dzeltilmesi iin bavuracak.
So let's say we got a case of bread-bottom, then my ingredient should actually be a
Diyelim ki bir de Brad dibinde bir vaka var, o zaman maddi madde aslnda olmal.
div with the following class name.
Sevgili snf ad ile.
Now for that, I need to import my classes so I will quickly add that, import classes from the burger
imdi, snflarm ie aktarmam gerekiyor, bylece Bruguera bileeni C S S dosyasndaki
ingredient css file and then I want to assign classes bread-bottom here
ie aktarma snflarn abucak ekleyeceim ve daha sonra olduunuzda Brad snflar atamak istiyorum.
and you can see that class in the css file
Ve DC indekslerinin snfn grebilirsiniz.
here, bread-bottom.
te Brad alt ksm.
We also have bread-top,
Hepimizin srlar var.
we have seeds for on the bread and then we got meat, cheese, salad and bacon.
Bratta koltuklarmz var ve et peyniri salatas ve pastrma var.
So here we create the bottom-bread just like that,
Yani burada alt ekmek retiriz.
let me add a semi-colon and then break.
Bir yar-kolon ekleyeyim ve sonra mola edeyim.
Now let's add another case,
imdi baka bir vaka daha ekleyelim.
the second case I want to check for is that we have bread-top.
Kontrol etmek istediim ikinci dava da ekmek tabamn olmas.
This actually requires a bit of a different ingredient not just a single div but on the top bread,
bir maddenin sadece bir lm gerektirir, ancak stteki ekmekte baz koltuklar olacaktr.
there shall be some seeds.
Bu aslnda biraz farkl
So here I actually return some multi-line jsx where the outer div also receives class name and then
Yani burada aslnda baz ok satrl J, X olarak d div da Clauss ad ve daha sonra
classes.BreadTop.
Klaas'n ekmek topu alr dnmek.
But inside there, I need two other divs which represent the seeds,
Ama ieride koltuklar temsil eden Obert cihazna ihtiyacm var.
so on the first div, I'll add class name and then I have classes.Seeds1 and I'll duplicate this to
Bylece snfn adnn ilk gnnde ve daha sonra snflarn koltuklar var ve hepsinin de koltuklar olan
also have a div with seeds2.
bir div olmas iin oaltacam.
So this is the alternative,
Yani alternatif budur.
let's also break here and now we can continue. The next case is that we have meat let's say, if
bir sonraki davaya devam edelim, bulualm, et var m diye ekleyelim diyelim ki bulualm.
we have meat then ingredient should be a div
Hepimiz burada bir mola verelim ve
and on that div, we will use class name and you guessed it classes.Meat. Now
Ve o gn snf ismini kullanacak olursak ve tahmin edersen snflar imdi buluur.
feel free to complete this for all the other ingredients, you can see which these are in the css file
Bunlar C S S dosyasnda grebileceiniz ortalama gradyanlar iin bunlar tamamlamaktan ekinmeyin
and simply create all cases for all ingredients you can identify here.
ve burada tanmlayabileceiniz tm ierikler iin tm vakalar oluturun.
I'll give you a chance to pause the video and try this on your own and then we'll do it together.
Sana makarna yapman iin bir ans vereceim ve bunu tek banza deneyip sonra birlikte yapacaz.
Were you successful? Let's now complete this together.
Baarl olsaydn bunu birlikte tamamlayalm.
It's actually pretty straightforward,
Aslnda olduka basittir.
We can now just copy the meat and enter it a couple of times here to also have cases for the cheese where
peynir vakalarn, ardndan pastrma snfn uyguladmz pastrmay yapmak iin de yapamayz.
we apply the classes cheese class, then the bacon where we apply the bacon class
Sadece eti kopyalayamayz ve birka kez buraya girerek, peynir snfn uyguladmz
and then finally the salad where we apply the salad class
Ve sonunda salata snfn uyguladmz salata.
and by the way if you want to implement this differently, and there certainly are alternatives to this
Bu arada, bunu farkl bir ekilde uygulamak istiyorsanz ve tabii ki bu byk
big switch case, you are of course more than free to do so.
anahtar ama seeneine alternatifleriniz varsa tabii ki bunu yapmak daha zgrdr.
Now let's also set up a default case here in case something incorrect is passed in
imdi hepsi yanl bir eyin getii durumda varsaylan bir durum oluturdu.
and there again, ingredient shall be null. Now after this gigantic switch statement here, we can safely return
Ingridion Shelby, yine burada bulunan bu dev deiim ifadesinin ardndan u maddeyi gvenle geri getirebiliriz:
the ingredient here and ingredient is either null or one of our many divs.
Ingrection u ana kadar ya da birok lmmzden biridir.
Now here's a thing we can do and we will actually do in the next lecture, we can add prop type validation
konferansta gerekten yapacamz bir ilem nk bir type zellii aldmzdan emin olmak istiyoruz.
to it because we want to make sure that we do receive a type property.
imdi yapabileceimiz bir ey var: Propp tr dorulamasnda yapabileceimiz bir sonraki
Now try this on your own,
imdi bunu kendi banza deneyin.
feel free to try this on your own. In the next lecture, we'll together add the prop types package and add
Bir sonraki ders dnyasnda Prop borularnn paketlenmesinden sonra Gabr'a bunu kendi banza denemekten
a prop type to verify that the type property really is passed into this component.
ekinmeyin ve tip zelliklerin gerekten bu bileene geirildiini dorulamak iin Rob Taieb'i ekleyin.